Cody Stair

 ♥ Clinton, TN
 ■ staircody27@gmail.com
 ▶ https://codystair.github.io
 ♠ codystair

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer based in Knoxville, TN. I'm the co-creator of Stagehand ②, a drop-in framework that automates the deployment and management of review apps for modern frontend applications. I have multiple years of experience in both the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, as well as Amazon Web Services (AWS) and Google Cloud Platform (GCP).

Skills

Backend	Frontend	Tooling	Cloud
Ruby, Rails, Sinatra,	HTML/CSS, JavaScript,	Git/GitHub, GitHub	AWS, Digital Ocean,
Node.js, PostgreSQL,	jQuery, React, Next,	Actions, Linux, Jira,	Heroku, Google Cloud
Express, RESTful APIs	GraphQL, TypeScript	Codefresh	Platform

Professional Experience

2021 - present

Full Stack Engineer, Caribou (formerly MotoRefi)

- Developed and maintained our company's internal applications
- Migrated our entire marketing site from using GraphCMS to Contentful
- Developed design documents and proof of concepts for various engineering initiatives
- Designed and implemented a large data migration from a Google Firestore collection to a PostgreSQL database
- Built a data pipeline to migrate customer info from our Rails monolith to Salesforce
- Quickly learned new technologies and tools in order to rapidly meet business needs
- Helped decouple the frontend of a large Rails app and rebuilt it in React/Next
- Collaborated daily with the engineering team, product team, and other departments in remote environment

2020 - 2021

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand

- Co-created Stagehand, an open-source drop-in solution that automates review apps for frontend applications
- Designed cloud infrastructure on AWS to host frontend review apps
- Prototyped and built GitHub integration to automatically deploy and tear down review apps using GitHub Actions
- Automated provisioning of AWS infrastructure using AWS CloudFormation
- Implemented client-side functionality for review apps to provide dashboard and handle routing using HTML iframe elements and service workers
- Built a robust easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away configuration and deployment logic, available as an NPM package
- Collaborated daily with a 100% remote team of engineers
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study: https://stagehand-framework.github.io

 □

2017 - 2020

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

 Developed mostly open-source software using Rails, Sinatra, Ruby, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React/Redux, vanilla JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

Education

2011 - 2013

Liberty University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Religion/Religious Studies